Guide to the James Weldon Johnson Collection Files
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Weldon Johnson collection files
1809-1979
JWJ MSS 114
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.5
(18 boxes)
The James Weldon Johnson Collection Files contain manuscript correspondence, literary works and other documents relating to African Americans, dating from 1809 to 1979. The collection contains several letters to James Weldon Johnson from aspiring poets asking for feedback on their writing. Correspondence sent to Langston Hughes, Harold Jackman, Grace Nail Johnson, and Carl Van Vechten is also prominent in the collection. The collection includes broadway actress Rose McClendon's scripts used when performing in various productions. Some early documents relate to slavery; these include bills of sale and an estate inventory dating from 1856. Writings by Sterling Allen Brown, George Washington Carver, Ralph Ellison, and J. Saunders Redding can be found in the collection. African-American women authors are also represented; most notably in writings and correspondence of Elizabeth Ross Haynes and Margaret Walker.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources. For more information see catalog cards filed in the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The James Weldon Johnson Collection Files contain letters, literary works and other documents arranged alphabetically by the name of author, recipient, or subject, and dating from 1809 to 1979.
The Files contain several letters, accompanied by poems, that were sent to James Weldon Johnson. Correspondence sent to Langston Hughes, Harold Jackman, Grace Nail Johnson and Carl Van Vechten is also prominent in the Files. Broadway actress Rose McClendon's scripts, used when performing in various productions, can also be found in Files.
Some early documents relate to slavery. These include correspondence and related materials dating from 1809 concerning Samuel Osborn who was accused of cutting off his slave's ear. The Files also include bills of sale and an estate inventory, which includes a list of slaves, dating from 1856.
Writings by a number of prominent twentieth century African-American intellectuals are included in the Files, such as Sterling Allen Brown, George Washington Carver, Ralph Ellison, and J. Saunders Redding.
Prominent African-American women authors are also represented, as seen in documents relating to Elizabeth Ross Haynes and Margaret Walker.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by the name of author, recipient, or subject.
African American authors -- 20th Century -- Archives; African American poets -- 20th Century; African American women authors; African Americans in literature; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- African American authors; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Slave bills of sale -- United States; Slave trade -- United States; Slavery -- United States; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Brown, Sterling A., 1901-1989; Carver, George Washington, 1864?-1943; Ellison, Ralph, 1914-1994; Haynes, Elizabeth Ross, 1883-1953; Jackman, Harold, 1901-1961; Johnson, Grace Nail, 1885-1976; Johnson, James Weldon, 1871-1938; McClendon, Rose, 1884-1936; Redding, J. Saunders (Jay Saunders), 1906-1988; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Walker, Margaret, 1915-1998
- "A"
  - Adams, Charles Francis Sr.
    - 1 autograph letter, signed, to unidentified correspondent, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1 autograph letter, signed, to F. W. Bird, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adelman, Lynn, "James Weldon Johnson: A Study in Negro Leadership," typescript, carbon, senior thesis (B.A.), History Department, Princeton University, 1961 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aldridge, Ira F., 2 autograph letters, signed, to unidentified correspondents, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alexander, Charles
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Garrison, Francis J.
  - Alexander, Mrs. John W., excerpts of letter to Prentiss Taylor, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alexander, Lewis, "Southland," autograph manuscript, signed, poem of two 8-line stanzas, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allen, George Leonard, poems, autograph manuscript, signed, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Poems include: "The 'Runt' Strikes Back," "Vision," "Ballade of Nordic Ideals," "Futility," "Portrait," "A Negro Salutes the Flay," "Twilight Fancy."
  - Andrew, John Albion, 4 autograph letters, signed, to Col. G. D. Wells, Col. Tompkins, and R. Fletcher, 1855, 1861-1863 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anthony, Helen B., "Two Worlds," short story, typescript, original, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Accompanied by typed excerpts from an untitled short story.
    Removed from Anthony's letter to James Weldon Johnson, August 14, 1934.
  - Atlanta University, documents, 1927-1937; 2 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    Contains: President Myron Winslow Adams' reports to the Trustees, 1927-1929, typescript, carbon; Ink sketch of property owned by Atlanta University, undated; Miscellaneous reports and statements concerning the Board of Trustees, etc., typescripts, originals and carbons, 1929-1937. Also includes list of Atlanta University graduates and ex-students in the New York City vicinity, 'confidential report' containing summary of critical opinions on Atlanta University presidential candidates
- "B"
  - Bacon, Rev. B. C., 1 autograph letter, signed, to David T. Kimball, 1834 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Barclay, Arthur, 1 typed letter, signed, to T. McCants Stewart, 1910 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barnett, Claude A., 1 typed letter, signed, to Ernest Hemby, 1931 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    See also: Carver, George Washington
  - Barth, Richmond, 1 autograph letter, signed, to Thomas Rutherford, 1940 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Batten, Edward A., "To the Creator of Lasca," poem, typescript. Poem dedicated "to the author of Nigger Heaven ", undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Removed from envelope addressed to Carl Van Vechten, June 1936.
  - Battle, Effie T., poems, typescripts, signed, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Poems include: "Mother Nature Takes a Hand," "To a Violet."
  - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1 autograph letter, signed, to unidentified correspondent, 1856 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bennett, Gwendolyn B., 5 autograph letters and 1 typed letter, signed, to Harold Jackman, 1925-26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bethea, Ednah, poems, typescripts, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Poems include: "Spring," "Dawn," "Night," "Life." Also included is an untitled poem with the first line "Why do I write? Is it passion, love?"
  - Bethune, Mary McLeod, 1 typed letter to the Spingarn Medal Committee of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, copy, 1935 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    See also: Sottong, Agnes M.
  - Blackburn, Alfred D., poems, autograph manuscript, signed, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Poems include: "To Jeanne Paltier," "To James Weldon Johnson: The Master's Violin."
  - Blooah, Charles G., "The War Title of Kaeweledjikpwamo, Greatest of Djabo Warriors Who Resided in Nimiah. He Died in About the Year 1900", undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Poem, in two parts: "The March to the Sea" and "Warrior, Thou Hunger." Includes typescript of Djabo translation.
  - Brandt, Barbara, 1 autograph letter, signed, to James Weldon Johnson, includes poems, 1930 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brandt, Zelma, poem, untitled poem with first line: "Sisters and brothers do not weep!", autograph manuscript copy, signed, 1938 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Brasher, Juliette, "The Life of Mr. Johnson," graduation paper, International School, Detroit, Michigan, 1935 December 30 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes an autograph letter, signed, from Brasher to James Weldon Johnson.
  - Bright, John, 2 letters to William Hicks, Sir Joshua Wolmsly, 1857, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brown, Francis J., outline for "Our Racial and National Minorities," typescript, carbon, with author's manuscript corrections and mimeographed list of topics sent to James Weldon Johnson concerning his chapters in Brown's book, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Brown, Sterling Allen
    - A Negro Looks at the South, autograph manuscript, working drafts of three chapters, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Drafts of poems, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Poems include: "Sharecropper," "Old Lem," and "The Last Ride of Wild Bill." With an autograph letter signed from Brown to (Alain) Locke, "Thursday Afternoon."
    - Southern Road: Poems, typescript, carbon, published: New York, Harcourt, Brace & Co., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Buckmaster, Henrietta, Fire in the Heart, typescripts, original, with author's manuscript corrections, circa 1948; 2 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of the author, 1949.
  - Burleigh, Harry Thacker
    - Armistice Day Program, Harriet Beecher Stowe Junior High School, class 8A1, manuscript, featuring H.T. Burleigh's "Study War No More" in a special arrangement, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 2 letters to Jeanette M. Thurber, 1911, 1937 November 8, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Includes biographical sketch of Burleigh, typescript.
  - Burr, Amelia Josephine, "The Flirt," poem, autograph manuscript, signed, poem of two 8-line stanzas, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Burrill, Mary, Aftermath, typescript, carbon, one-act play, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Burrus, James Dallas, biographical material about James Dallas Burrus, 1875-1878, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Contains "Some notes on his life as told by Mary E. Spence, Professor Emeritus of Fisk University," typescript, carbon; "Jubilee Romance," possibly written by Mary E. Spence, typescript, original; 41 typed letter copies from America W. Robinson to Burrus, dated March 4th, 1875-April 14th, 1878, various places, with summary list of letters included, accompanied by an autograph note signed by Grace Nail Johnson.
    Given by Mrs. Johnson, October 1967.
- "C"
  - Calhoun, John C., autograph letter, signed to John Law, "on the increase of slaves in proportion to the free population", 1821 July 28 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Includes carbon copy and transcription.
    Gift of William H. Crawford.
  - Campbell, Mrs. E. Sims, 1937 April 8-1937 June 19
    - Willis, Mr. and Mrs., 2 typed letters, signed, to Mr. and Mrs. Willis (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Peterson, Sidney, 2 typed letters, signed, to Peterson (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Willis, Mr. and Mrs., 12 letters, signed, to Mr. and Mrs. Willis and family (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Carrington, Glenn, The Employment Problem of the New York State Negro Prisoner: A Proposed Solution, typescript, carbon, with manuscript corrections, 1943 February 11 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Thesis for the degree of Master of Science at Columbia University. With mailing envelope addressed to "Carl Van Vechten, Esquire."
  - Carson, Lular L., 1 autograph letter, signed, to "Don", 1971 August 19 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Carter, Elmer Anderson
    See: Sottong, Agnes M.
  - Carter, Herman J. D., "Begging for Love," typescript original, poem in two 8-line stanzas, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Carver, George Washington
    - Barnett, Claude A., correspondence, 1942 June-July (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Includes 2 from Carver, 1 from Barnett.
    - Hill, Harvey J., correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Purchased, JWJ Fund, April 1970.
      Includes 17 from Carver to Hill, and 11 from Hill to Carver.
    - Hill, Harvey J., correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Includes 43 from Carver to Hill, and also includes 1 from "TDJ" to Carver, 1 from E. Connolly to Hill, 1 from "Floyd" to Hill, 1 from A. H. Curtis to Hill.
  - Caver, Theresa, poems, typescripts, original, 9 signed, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Poems include: "Birthright," "Before Her Wedding Day," "Twilight," "A Mother's Universe," "Recompense," "Contemplative Poplars," "To a Wild Flower," "Contentment," "Serenity," "Secret Tears," "White Corridors."
  - Champain, Clara, "A Six-Pointed Star," typescript, original, essay on her first Christmas in America, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Also includes advertising flier and mailing envelope addressed to Langston Hughes from "Mrs. White."
  - Chaplin, Ralph, "Mourn Not the Dead," poem, typescript, original, signed, poem of three 4-line stanzas, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Chapman, Maria Weston, 1 autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Garrison, 1885 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Child, Lydia Maria, 1 autograph letter, signed, to unnamed correspondent, Wayland, 1856 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Christian, Marcus B.
    - 1 typed letter, carbon, from Christian to Dean Bond, dated February 23, 1939, on sending Bond copies of his poems. With 1 typed letter signed, "first draft," from Christian to L(yle) Saxon, dated October 28, 1942, thanking him for a gift, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - "In Memoriam Franklin Delano Roosevelt," poem, typescript, original, first draft with author's corrections and revisions, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
      Also includes page proofs in various states.
    - Poems, mimeographed typescripts, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
      Poems include "Could I," "Souvenir," "My Life," "Neu Yeah-Lawd! Lawd!," "Bow Down Niggah, Bow Down!," and "Go South, Young Man."
    - Poems, typescripts, originals and carbons, signed, with publication notes in the author's hand, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Poems commemorating Franklin Delano Roosevelt, typescripts, original, first drafts, 1945 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Also included are untitled poems with first lines "The stalwart one we know..." I hear a nation mourning..." "You walked with great men..." "The great heart born within our span of lives..."
    - "The Teacher," poem, autograph manuscript, signed, "A parody of William Blake's 'The Tiger,' written after reading The Times ' account of the investigation of Communist activities in American colleges," four page proofs in various states, with some author's corrections, 1953 March 4 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Gift of the author, 1953 March 11.
    - ---, autograph manuscript, signed, with draft of an imprint statement, circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      Gift of the author, received 1953 March 11.
  - Cobden, Richard, 1 autograph letter, signed, to W. H. Osborne, Scotland, one page missing, 1862 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Cocteau, Jean, 1 autograph letter, signed, to Chester Himes, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Cole, Bob, The Wrong Man, typescript, carbon, "A 1-act musical farcem" with annotation on first leaf in the hand of J. Rosamond Johnson, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Collins, Durward, "The Cockfighter," poem, typescript, original. Poem inscribed by Carl Van Vechten, September 5, 1962, draft with author's corrections and additional notes on verso, circa 1962 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Cook, Mercer, "Gratien Candace, Negro," typescript, original, sent from editor of Reader's Digest to James Weldon Johnson, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Cook, Will Marion, "School for Negro Music," typed copy, to "Mr. Adler," on establishing a school in New York city for the study of Negro music, undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Cooper, Mrs. George, 1 autograph letter, signed, to Ida Himes, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Crawford, Abigail E., "A Program for Catholic Collegians," typescript, original, signed by Crawford, with author's corrections and notes, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Culbertson, Ernest H., 1 autograph letter, signed, to Henry Lower, 1922 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Culver, Dwight, Negro Segregation in the Methodist Church, setting typescript, original, with the author's corrections and publisher's editorial markings, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    Published: New Haven, Yale University Press, 1953. Yale Studies in Religious Education.
  - Cuney, Waring
    - Jim Crow Blues, typescript, original, signed, with author's corrections, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 71)
      "Poems of protest" recorded by Josh White on the album Southern Exposure, Keynote Records, Inc., N.Y. Poems include "Defense Factory Blues," "Hard Time Blues," "Jim Crow Blues," "Bad Housing Blues," "Jim Crow Train Blues," "Leaving Here Blues."
    - Mississippi Story (And Other Blues Poems), typescripts, original and carbon, signed, Elgin Field, Florida, 1942 November 4-26 (Box 3, Folder 72)
      Poems include "Mississippi Story," "Hollow Log Blues," "No Name Blues," "Hard Hearted Judge Blues," "Mistreatin' Blues."
    - Poems, autograph manuscript, signed, and typescripts, originals and carbons, with some author's corrections, 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 73)
      Gift of the author, 1943-1945.
      Poems include "Sergeant Dusty," autograph manuscript and typescript; "Dusty and Lucky Agree," autograph manuscript; "Big Talk," autograph manuscript; "When the Lights Go On," autograph manuscript; "Down Home Boy," autograph manuscript; "Turkey Breast," autograph manuscript and typescript, carbon; "They Might Near Fit," autograph manuscript, photocopy, and typescript, original; "Lonesome Place," autograph manuscript, photocopy; "Cool Fool," autograph manuscript, photocopy; "Monty Roberts' Baby Stew," autograph manuscript; "Ward Slip," autograph manuscript; "Two Worlds," autograph manuscript. The photocopies of the manuscripts "Lonesome Place" and "Cool Fool" are V-mail letters to the James Weldon Johnson collection. "They Might Near Fit" is a V-mail letter to Langston Hughes, September 4, 1943, San Francisco, California.
    - Poems, typescripts, carbons, fifteen poems inscribed by Cuney for Carl Van Vechten, with envelope, 1947 November 23 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      Poems include "Sergeant Dusty," "Lame Man and the Blind Man," "Chow-time Chick," "Me and My Cap'n," "Saturday Night Talk," "Hard Time Blues," "A Prayer," "Little Girl," "Cap'n Wishes," "Leaving Here," "Bessie Smith," "Stella and Joe," "Turkey Breast," "So Long," "Thought of My True Love."
      Gift of Carl Van Vechten.
    - Poems, typescripts, original, circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      Poems include "Little Girl," "I Thought of My True Love," "Four Little Pictures of My True Love," "Why Call Her Name," "Tell Irene Hello," "Lame Man and the Blind Man," "Nan," "Three in a Row," "The Lonesome Yellow," "Summer Burial." Ten poems inscribed for Mrs. James Weldon Johnson, May 2, 1949.
  - Curtis, Constance G., poems, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
    Poems include: "To a Lone Negro in a Small Town" and "Reverie."
- "D"
  - Danko, poem, "Ho-Ho! Boli Boys," typescript, 1923, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
    Includes a biographical note on Danko from Mitchell Dawson's "Danko: The Emperor's Archangel," in The Double Dealer, New Orleans, November 1923.
  - Darrow, Clarence, 1 typed letter, signed, from G. T. Standalls, 1931 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Darrow, Mrs. Clarence, 1 autograph letter, signed, from Bernice Powel, 1928 February 6 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Davis, Frank M., poems, typescripts, carbon, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    Poems include: "Chicago Congo (Sonata for an orchestra)"; "Tryst...." (melody for the tenor strings of a harp), an excerpt from "Love Cycle"; excerpts from "Ebony Under Granite," including "Arthur Ridgewood, M.D." "Acey White," "Rev. Joseph Williams."
  - Davis, Marjorie E., poems, typescripts, original, 1932 March 29 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    Poems include: "Hungry Faces, " "Blades of Grass," "To Edna St. Vincent Millay," "New York," "Spring." Removed from her autograph letter signed to James Weldon Johnson, March 29, 1932.
  - Davis, Nolan Hartford, Six Black Horses, setting typescript, xerox, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    Separated Materials
    Published: New York, Putnam, 1971.
    Gift of Book of the Month Club.
  - Deutsch, Monroe E., "Is Internationalism Out of Fashion?" typescript, carbon, text of a speech delivered December 10, 1933 at the Institute of World Affairs, Riverside, California, with quotes from James Weldon Johnson's Along This Way (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Dixon, Ozelia J., "And Little Children Loved Him," typescript, original, signed, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    Poem commemorating Franklin Delano Roosevelt. Inscribed 1945, Houston, Texas, in hand of Langston Hughes.
  - Donahoe, Edward, Ada Bell: 1900-1921, typescript, original. A story, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Douglas, Aaron, "Party for Grace and James Weldon Johnson," broadside invitation, with illustration by Aaron Douglas, printed by the Studio of Mr. Charles H. Studin, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
    Signed by Dorothy Peterson, Anna K. Braxton, Elizabeth Shaffer, Lucile V. Miller, Carl Van Vechten, Nora E. Johnson, Esther Junger, Bertha B. Randolph, Grace F. Nail.
    Gift of Mrs. J. W. Johnson.
  - Dover, Cedric
    - Brown Phoenix, poems, typescript, carbon, setting copy with editorial marks and a few author's corrections, before 1950 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - ---, galley proofs, with the author's autograph note signed with initials to the publisher, 1950 July 27 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - ---, galley proofs, as published: London, College Press, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - ---, publisher's paste-up, with a few author's corrections and with original pencil drawing on last page, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Essay on poetry, typescript, carbon, incomplete, undated (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Feathers in the Arrow; an Approach for Coloured Writers and Readers, printer's dummy. With Dover's autograph additions and printed article laid in, and with his editorial markings and corrections, circa 1947 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - DuBois, Shirley Graham
    - Notes on George Washington Carver, autograph manuscript, with miscellaneous typed notes and printed material, notes and ideas for her book, Dr. George Washington Carver, George D. Lipscomb, joint author, circa 1944 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Paul Robeson, Citizen of the World, typescript, original, with author's manuscript corrections and publisher's editorial markings, includes a foreward by Carl Van Doren, circa 1946 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Duff, Dorothy, Mrs. Brown's Body, typescript, original, one-act play, with a few author's corrections, undated (Box 4, Folder 95)
    Gift of Harold Jackman. See HJ to CVV, 04/26/57.
  - Dunlap, Ethel Lee, poems, autograph manuscripts, undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
    Poems include: "People Will Talk," "The Prayer of a Slave," and "Ethel Lee Dunlap."
- "E"
  - Ellis, Lester M., poems, typescript, original, 1 signed, with author's autograph notes on verso of signed leaf, undated (Box 4, Folder 97)
    Poems include: "Comrade I Reply" and "Two Birds," the latter published in the Kansas City Journal Post, January 11, 1935.
  - Ellison, Ralph
    - The King of the Bingo Game, typescript, original, signed, draft, with author's note, corrections and autograph leaf laid in, 1943 October 22 (Box 4, Folder 98)
      Gift of the author through Langston Hughes and Carl Van Vechten, 1943.
    - ---, typescript, original, signed, marked "draft 2," with author's corrections (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Embree, Edwin R., "Shall the South Accept Mediocrity?" typescript, carbon, circa 1932 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    Address delivered at Tennessee College Association, Nashville, March 25, 1932.
  - Encyclopedia of the Negro, preliminary reports, press releases, letters, etc. concerning publication of the Encyclopedia, typescript, mimeographed and carbon, 1931-1936 (Box 5, Folder 101)
- "F"
  - Fauset, Jessie
    - 4 autograph letters, signed, and 5 typed letters, signed, to Harold Jackman, 1 typed letter includes handwritten additions, 1924-1942 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Autograph letter, signed, to Mrs. James Weldon Johnson, written on postcard from Algiers, Algeria, 1925 January 19 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Removed from book by Jessie Fauset given to library by Mrs. J. W. J.